<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://michaelloistl.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://michaelloistl.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-11-27T09:27:08+00:00</updated><id>https://michaelloistl.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Michael Loistl</title><subtitle>Programmer, Maker and Digital Nomad</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Revit Family App “Early Access”</title><link href="https://michaelloistl.com/2020/11/26/rfa-early-access" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Revit Family App “Early Access”" /><published>2020-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://michaelloistl.com/2020/11/26/rfa-early-access</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://michaelloistl.com/2020/11/26/rfa-early-access">&lt;p&gt;Normally I run a week of discounted sale for &lt;a href=&quot;https://revit-content.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;All-in-One Revit Families&lt;/a&gt;, beginning with Cyber Monday, but this year I wanted to extend this offer into the current week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could have started from Monday but was too busy working on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://revitfamily.app/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Revit Family App&lt;/a&gt;, that it was Wednesday before I got to write the “Black Friday” - “Cyber Monday” email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As soon as I started to write the email, I couldn’t stop thinking about the current state of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://revitfamily.app/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Revit Family App&lt;/a&gt;, and that it would actually be time to share this new exciting product with at least a small group of really interested people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is still tons of work to do before it’s ready for a public release, but at the same time it’s now at a point where I would love to share it with people who are really interested to get their hands on and give early feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m myself very interested in the early days of products, their development, peaks behind the scenes etc., so I thought why not getting myself out of my comfort zone and start to share the entire journey from now till the public release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could obviously share that also publicly, but it is a first time for me and it’s definitely outside of my comfort zone,  so I rather start doing that with a closed group and get slowly  into public sharing in the course towards a public release (maybe even public beta).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, I ended up writing the following in that email to all my existing &lt;a href=&quot;https://revit-content.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Revit Content&lt;/a&gt; customers and subscribers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m now looking for a group of early adaptors, that would like to &lt;strong&gt;get early access&lt;/strong&gt; and want to &lt;strong&gt;get involved in the process&lt;/strong&gt; of bringing the Revit Family App to a public release.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This group will be &lt;strong&gt;limited to 100 people&lt;/strong&gt; in order to keep it productive and to be able to be in touch individually.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;You will &lt;strong&gt;get access to a private Slack group, be the first to see and play with the app, and follow the development, design and product decisions and more.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I want to share the entire journey with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;You will be able to &lt;strong&gt;create families for free&lt;/strong&gt; until the app will be publicly released.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;You also &lt;strong&gt;receive 250 credits&lt;/strong&gt; that you can use once the app has been released publicly, where 1 credit will be charged for each family created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also decided to make that “Early Access” paid, as I want this group of early adopters to be really committed. I priced it with $249, which is essentially the price for the included 250 credits but also includes complete free use until the public release on top of the being able to getting involved in the product development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far a good number of mostly loyal, long time customers have joined the “Early Access” which means a lot to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned earlier, I want to limited the “Early Access” to 100 people, but please &lt;a href=&quot;https://gum.co/rfa_early_access&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;check this page&lt;/a&gt; in case you would like to join. I’d be thrilled to have you on board!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="rfa" /><summary type="html">Normally I run a week of discounted sale for All-in-One Revit Families, beginning with Cyber Monday, but this year I wanted to extend this offer into the current week.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A lot has happened</title><link href="https://michaelloistl.com/2020/11/19/a-lot-has-happened" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A lot has happened" /><published>2020-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://michaelloistl.com/2020/11/19/a-lot-has-happened</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://michaelloistl.com/2020/11/19/a-lot-has-happened">&lt;p&gt;… since I wrote here back in September. We have met wonderful people, explored more of Madeira and have officially received the Portuguese Residence, which allows us to stay here no matter what’s the outcome from that crazy Brexit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have been able to consistently release one new video per week (that’s 10 new videos) on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/lauzaandmichael&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Youtube channel&lt;/a&gt;, capturing our experiences for ourself and a growing follower-ship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We just hit 500 subscribers yesterday, but those make only a small part of our active viewers which is really encouraging. We receive more and more really positive comments and messages from true Madeira lovers and  even met one couple that is regularly watching our videos while we had lunch in Calheta, which was very unexpected but super special. We have also enjoyed various hikes with lovely people from Germany and Austria which since join us weekly to enjoy those beautiful Madeira experiences while being back at their homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this last 10 weeks, my progress on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://revitfamily.app&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Revit Family App&lt;/a&gt; was not as steady as I was hoping for, as I hit multiple road blocks that needed some creative solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, for the last two weeks all the major roadblocks have been resolved and this last few days I have for the first time been able to actually generate custom families directly from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://revitfamily.app&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Revit Family App&lt;/a&gt; Editor. That’s a huge milestone for me, that I was working towards for a really long time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There shouldn’t be any major roadblocks ahead, which means that the early access program should finally be possible to start at the beginning of December. I have already promised to so many eagerly waiting customers that they can get their hands on this super exciting new product and I can’t wait to be ready for sending them their personal invite to join me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan is to run the early access program for 1-2 month to get as much as possible feedback and complete what’s missing for the public release at the beginning of 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in joining the &lt;em&gt;Early Access Program&lt;/em&gt;, please do &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:michael@revit-content.com&quot;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt; with me.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">… since I wrote here back in September. We have met wonderful people, explored more of Madeira and have officially received the Portuguese Residence, which allows us to stay here no matter what’s the outcome from that crazy Brexit.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">It’s ok to have bad days</title><link href="https://michaelloistl.com/2020/09/08/it-is-ok-to-have-bad-days" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="It’s ok to have bad days" /><published>2020-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://michaelloistl.com/2020/09/08/it-is-ok-to-have-bad-days</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://michaelloistl.com/2020/09/08/it-is-ok-to-have-bad-days">&lt;p&gt;It’s now the second day since I’m back full time on &lt;a href=&quot;https://revitfamily.app&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;RFA&lt;/a&gt; after a freelance related break, and to be honest, the first day totally sucked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt totally overwhelmed, trying to figure out how to compute all the 3d vertices in the most efficient way with the least number of faces, while implementing a custom sweep geometry in the upcoming &lt;a href=&quot;https://revitfamily.app&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;RFA&lt;/a&gt; editor. I started the day late with a weekend style breakfast and the quite hot temparetures during the day just made me want to do anything but code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than making myself wrong for not being productive, I acknowledged the fact, and did my very best to just use the time for a walk, some food shopping and catching up on some reading, watching and listing of bookmarked content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today started intentional with a morning run at 7am along the new coastal road, followed by a shower and a much shorter breakfast then yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This morning routine felt refreshing and put me in a much better position to start working on the complex issue that I couldn’t wrap my head around yesterday. While still challenging, it felt somehow effortless today, working step by step towards a solution. I kinda figured out the now implemented solution during my walk to food shopping yesterday, so while this felt unproductive yesterday, it helped a lot to make today a productive day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are still a few key features that I must figure out and build in a simple but  functional way before I get a better handle on a realistic timeline for the planned early access. However, today’s progress gave me definitely a positive push in the right direction and I just have to acknowledge that it takes a few days to transition form freelance iOS work back into some complex web development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It takes time to transition between domains and there are bad, non productive days in between, that’s just a fact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today’s temperature during the day was also much more comfortable than expected. The weather forecast showed the hottest day of the week which was supposed to feel really humid, however it wasn’t that bad and the portable vent we have next to our desk was actually enough to feel comfortable. Towards the end of this week, the temperature is supposed to go down with some rain forecast for the weekend, which sounds really refreshing after 2 month of nothing but sunshine. Not complaining, just saying…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lauza started to edit our next &lt;a href=&quot;https://lauzaandmichael.com/youtube&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; episode yesterday, which should go out this coming Thursday. Tomorrow I’ll focus on cleaning up today’s editor implementation and focus on coding more or less during the first half of the day, while editing our next episode together with Lauza for the rest of the day. This is something that I truly enjoy every week, so looking forward to it…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">It’s now the second day since I’m back full time on RFA after a freelance related break, and to be honest, the first day totally sucked.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My first productive week</title><link href="https://michaelloistl.com/2020/07/17/my-first-productive-week" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My first productive week" /><published>2020-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://michaelloistl.com/2020/07/17/my-first-productive-week</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://michaelloistl.com/2020/07/17/my-first-productive-week">&lt;p&gt;Now, where I’ve the full working week to myself, I don’t have to squeeze working on my own projects into the early morning or late evening hours anymore. I can actually organise my days in a healthier and more productive fashion, taking more time for myself, read and write more, write code when I’m the most focused and work on marketing and other content related topics in between. I don’t have to stick to a fix 10am-6pm schedule and depending on how my days go, I can work more or less hours, earlier or later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One particular change that my wife and I started to do since the beginning of this week has been to go for a morning swim at the nearby beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2020-07-17-my-first-productive-week/morning-swim-madeira.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, it took some convincing of myself, as my default would be to get up and start working, rather then spending time for my well-being or even fun. Just the thought of jumping into the cold Atlantic Ocean as one of the first things in the morning wasn’t particularly appealing to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, my wife successfully convinced me to give it a try and to my surprise, I actually enjoyed it. First, the water isn’t cold at all, which is apparently a thing here on Madeira due to it’s location as well as the lava sand, and second, I felt so much more refreshed and started my actual working day in a much more productive way than usual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t want to fully credit this productive week solely on our new morning routine (which we managed to do 4 out of 5 days), but it has been a super productive week, completing my first project of redesigning the &lt;a href=&quot;https://revit-content.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Revit Content website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week I’m going to dive fully into coding on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://revitfamily.app&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Revit Family App&lt;/a&gt; and kicking off the creation of the long overdue documentation for all of the Revit Families.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">Now, where I’ve the full working week to myself, I don’t have to squeeze working on my own projects into the early morning or late evening hours anymore. I can actually organise my days in a healthier and more productive fashion, taking more time for myself, read and write more, write code when I’m the most focused and work on marketing and other content related topics in between. I don’t have to stick to a fix 10am-6pm schedule and depending on how my days go, I can work more or less hours, earlier or later.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Countdown &amp;amp; Commitment</title><link href="https://michaelloistl.com/2020/07/08/countdown-commitment" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Countdown &amp;amp; Commitment" /><published>2020-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://michaelloistl.com/2020/07/08/countdown-commitment</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://michaelloistl.com/2020/07/08/countdown-commitment">&lt;p&gt;During my daily session of blog post reading, two posts stood out for me as very relevant to my current situation. The first &lt;a href=&quot;https://seths.blog/2020/07/the-magic-of-the-countdown&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The magic of the countdown&lt;/a&gt; by Seth Godin and the second &lt;a href=&quot;https://alearningaday.blog/2020/07/08/focus-intensity-hard-work-and-inevitability&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Focus, intensity, hard work, and inevitability&lt;/a&gt; by Rohan Rajiv.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These last few days feel like a countdown towards a new beginning in my professional journey, despite the fact that I have been working on &lt;a href=&quot;https://revit-content.com&quot;&gt;Revit Content&lt;/a&gt; on and off for the last 10 years and on &lt;a href=&quot;https://revitfamily.app&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Revit Family App&lt;/a&gt; for more than 1 year. It feels that way as these two projects are going to turn from side projects into my full time work and sole source of income (besides the one or other freelance project).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seth writes about countdown:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But what really matters is this: There’s a commitment.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;When we get to zero, we’re actually going to do this.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The commitment has to happen before the countdown can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I read this part, I realised that I’ve built up this commitment over quite some time and that I’m ready for the Focus x Intensity x Hard Work to start, which Rohan defines as follow…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus&lt;/strong&gt; is the continuous, iterative, process of keeping the main thing the main thing. &lt;strong&gt;Intensity&lt;/strong&gt; is being 100% engaged while doing it. And, &lt;strong&gt;Hard Work&lt;/strong&gt; requires no further introduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While my current countdown is towards the beginning of my new full time journey, building my business, there was a countdown towards making and communicating the decision of taking this step (which was the commitment).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entire process of getting ready and finally doing it, took almost a year, including the final hand over and transition out of my CTO role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While my full focus during the last few days has still been to do my very best work as iOS &amp;amp; Ruby Developer for the NYC startup, the mornings and evenings are dedicated to working through the status quo of my own products and breaking down the first project in order to fully focus on execution from Monday next week.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">During my daily session of blog post reading, two posts stood out for me as very relevant to my current situation. The first The magic of the countdown by Seth Godin and the second Focus, intensity, hard work, and inevitability by Rohan Rajiv.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Transition time</title><link href="https://michaelloistl.com/2020/07/07/transition-time" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Transition time" /><published>2020-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://michaelloistl.com/2020/07/07/transition-time</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://michaelloistl.com/2020/07/07/transition-time">&lt;p&gt;As I get closer to the completion of my transition from my previous CTO role at a NYC startup to working full-time on my own projects, I am experiencing the “letting go”, to be much harder than I thought it would be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m used to work on my own projects and have done this full time in the past and during my free time over the last 2 years, however the transition of working for someone else full time to working full time for myself again is something I need to get my mind settled back into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is officially my last week and from next Monday all my energy will go into building out my business, which I’m super excited about. This is the moment that I have been working towards for such a long time that it feels somehow unreal, now where it’s finally here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to use this week to &lt;a href=&quot;https://basecamp.com/shapeup&quot;&gt;shape up&lt;/a&gt; and think deeper about the right problems to focus on first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are basically two main areas — one is my &lt;a href=&quot;https://revit-content.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;existing product&lt;/a&gt; which I want to release a bunch off content updates and bring the quite outdated documentation up to date, including a series of video screencasts for each of the revit families — and the other is my &lt;a href=&quot;https://revitfamily.app&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;new product&lt;/a&gt; that I started development on roughly one year ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I’m roughly around 2/3 there to get an early preview of &lt;a href=&quot;https://revitfamily.app&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Revit Family App&lt;/a&gt; released, but can’t really say how long that remaining work is going to take. During the last year it was a constant on and off which meant lots of wasted effort in getting back to where I left off. So part of this weeks shape up is to identify exactly where I’m at and break down the hard things that need to be solved and the scope that’s really necessary to build out before an early preview release is possible.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">As I get closer to the completion of my transition from my previous CTO role at a NYC startup to working full-time on my own projects, I am experiencing the “letting go”, to be much harder than I thought it would be.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Our travel continues</title><link href="https://michaelloistl.com/2020/07/06/our-travel-continues" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Our travel continues" /><published>2020-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://michaelloistl.com/2020/07/06/our-travel-continues</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://michaelloistl.com/2020/07/06/our-travel-continues">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2020-07-06-our-travel-continues/portugal_madeira.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started our slow travel journey back at the end of February this year, where we had no idea, or were at least ignorant about what was about to hit as a global pandemic. We spent the first month in Lisbon before we moved to Cotovia nearby Sesimbra for the following 3 month. While we extended our stay for a little longer then initially planned, we were eager to explore new areas and while the borders between various countries are still closed, travel within mainland Portugal  and its islands Madeira and Azores started to open up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Madeira and Porto Santo opened to international tourists from July 1st, with the requirement of presenting a negative Covid-19 test done within 72 hours prior to departure or to be tested upon arrival. You can find more details on travel to Madeira at their &lt;a href=&quot;https://madeirasafetodiscover.com/&quot;&gt;dedicated website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We couldn’t figure out how to get a test with the required time window at our previous location, so we took the test provided by the Madeira government and got confirmed negative around 6 hours after being tested. During this time we stayed at our accommodation which we were told is required procedure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we had no symptoms and were quite sure that we would be fine, it was nevertheless a big relief, having it officially confirmed. This is obviously just a moment in time that confirms that we were not infected at the time of testing, so we continue to be overly careful, avoiding any crowded places and protect ourselves and others by wearing masks and washing our hands regularly with soap or 96% alcohol while shopping or being in public places. We do whatever we can to stay safe and protect others, which I would think is a no brainer for everyone, but unfortunately I get proven wrong too many times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2020-07-06-our-travel-continues/portugal_madeira.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This latest change of scenery is also a milestone in my professional journey, getting closer to the completion of my transition from my previous CTO role at a NYC startup to working full-time on my own project as well as on some interesting freelance work as iOS and web developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent more than a year on building out an idea that started close to 10 years ago, and while it’s not yet ready to be launched, I feel close enough to invest more time into this project, so that I get it out into the world. As I’m transitioning to making this project my main focus, there is lots to learn and figure out, which I plan to write more about here on my personal blog going forward.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Understanding Men &amp;amp; Women</title><link href="https://michaelloistl.com/2020/04/05/understanding-men-and-women" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Understanding Men &amp;amp; Women" /><published>2020-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://michaelloistl.com/2020/04/05/understanding-men-and-women</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://michaelloistl.com/2020/04/05/understanding-men-and-women">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2020-04-05-understanding-men-and-women/lauza_and_michael.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wife and I are married for 12+ years and our relationship is getting stronger and stronger. We are both very much into personal development, and one of the programs that we have benefited from the most in our personal relationship as well as with others is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.understandmen.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Understanding Men &amp;amp; Women&lt;/a&gt; from Alison Armstrong. We are still at level 1 but the impact of what we have learned so far has been profound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding the principles that drive men and women in their masculine and feminine are fascinating and having this knowledge, helped me personally to understand so many of my own past life experiences and mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Until we understand the real differences in what compels our behavior, especially under stress, we’ll keep bringing out the worst in each other. And never experience the real beauty of both men and women.”
— *Alison Armstrong *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding that there is nothing wrong with me or the other person, and that we are by default mostly just acting from our instincts (without it even recognizing), helps a lot in being compassionate and understanding both sides. This creates a whole new level of conciousness and awareness in any kind of relationship, from my wife to family, friends, colleagues and strangers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is so profound that I would wish this to be taught to everyone before getting romantically or professionally involved with another person. We learn so much theoretical stuff in school, but the principles of how we interact and communicate between each other is something that is left for everyone to figure out on their own, causing so many unnecessary conflicts and disappointments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we started Alison’s curriculum we listened to her audio books &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.audible.co.uk/pd/Understanding-Women-Audiobook/B00B00G26K&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Amazing Development of Men&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.audible.co.uk/pd/Understanding-Women-Audiobook/B00B00G26K&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Understanding Women&lt;/a&gt;, which was a really good starting point, but if you are interested in that topic (which I highly recommend you to be) there is also some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.understandmen.com/free&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;free stuff&lt;/a&gt; to get started.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The fear of the unknown</title><link href="https://michaelloistl.com/2020/04/04/the-fear-of-the-unknown" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The fear of the unknown" /><published>2020-04-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-04-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://michaelloistl.com/2020/04/04/the-fear-of-the-unknown</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://michaelloistl.com/2020/04/04/the-fear-of-the-unknown">&lt;p&gt;It’s about one month since my last post (March 1st) and lots has changed in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we arrived to Lisbon, there were 0 (zero) confirmed cases of COVID-19 in Portugal and we were all but present about the impact of what we just observed in “other countries”. Just a few days in, the numbers started to climb in Portugal as they did all over the world, and at the time of writing this post, Portugal has 10,524 total cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stayed in Lisbon until end of March and had then to make a decision of extending our stay or moving as planned to our next destination (near Sesimbra), which is just a 30min car drive south of Lisbon, still in Portugal. This decision wasn’t an easy one as we really wanted to avoid moving. We booked that second Airbnb back in January based on its location outside of the city, close to nature as well as the southern coast line being in walking distance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we embarked on our slow traveling journey as digital nomads at the end of February, we were totally ok with heading off into the unknown, leaving everything behind. This time however, the decision to move on to the next destination felt really hard, despite it being just a small move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were supposed to move at the end of March, but postponed the move initially for a week to not fall into the period of the “state of emergency”, declared by the Portuguese government on March 19th. At the beginning of this week, we received a message from the Airbnb host of the next destination, informing us that the “state of emergency” will most likely be extended with the expectation of some additional measures which might make the move from Lisbon harder or impossible. He suggested that we should think about moving earlier (before Thursday) if we still would wanted to move at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sat down for a few hours, discussing the pros and cons and eventually decided to go for it. What made that decision so much harder compared with other much larger decisions (like giving up everything in London to become digital nomads) was the fear of moving (being exposed) and committing to a longer stay (nobody really know what’s going to happen over forseeable future) at a location that we knew not much about. On top of that, we don’t even know how long we can actually stay at this second destination, as there are existing bookings from mid May, although it’s likely that those will be canceled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally that would be totally fine as we stay for a while and move then on, but this time it felt like we wouldn’t know how long we would stay at that next location. The infrastructure in terms of supermarkets as well as the proximity to nature was theoretically so much better than we had in Lisbon, but at least we knew what we had in Lisbon, even there was just a small butcher, a few mini markets and a bakery nearby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is basically fear of the unknown, deeply ingrained in everyone, which causes most people to be comfortable being uncomfortable, like working in jobs that they hate, staying in relationships that don’t work, being sick from living an unhealthy lifestyle, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, we finally moved last Tuesday, making today the 4th day here at our second destination, which we are super happy to have decided for. Their are 3 larger super markets just 5 min down the street and being just minutes from the wast green area of “Parque Natural da Arrábida” is a really great area to spend an extended period of time at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2020-04-04-the-fear-of-the-unknown/portugal_sesimbra.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Song listened while writing this post: &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/3tPZnys7q5euIWahFjvro7?si=DQu4XIfoQ4OS133eKKkrHw&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lovely&lt;/a&gt; by Joey Pecoraro&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">It’s about one month since my last post (March 1st) and lots has changed in the world.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello World (literally)</title><link href="https://michaelloistl.com/2020/03/01/hello-world" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello World (literally)" /><published>2020-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://michaelloistl.com/2020/03/01/hello-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://michaelloistl.com/2020/03/01/hello-world">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Hello World” is often the first program written by people learning to code, and is often used to illustrate the basic syntax of a programming language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a programer and I have used those two words on many programming related occasions, however today I want to use them “literally” and say “Hello World” related to our new journey as digital nomads traveling the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About 2 month ago, my wife and I decided to give up our flat in East London to travel the world as digital nomads. I wrote about this decision and what got us to this point in &lt;a href=&quot;https://michaelloistl.com/20200202-our-next-chapter&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Our next chapter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2020-03-01-hello-world/hello_world.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have since cleared our flat and reduced our belongings to one suitcase, one carry-on luggage and a backpack (check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/p/B9KqffYlzJ8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this instagram post&lt;/a&gt; to see us and everything we take with us), and yesterday we took a one-way flight to Lisbon (Portugal) where we spend our first 4 weeks before moving further south.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although we had spent the last few weeks preparing for this new chapter in our lives, the actual departure from London felt more like going on holiday rather than a one way flight into a new way of living, which was quite interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For us, this new chapter is not just a change of location(s) but a new start of creative work we both want to focus on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to be an architect but transitioned into software development over the last 10 years. Now it’s time to bring those two professions back together with a new service for architects, that I have been working on during my free time  for the better part of the last year. I’ll share more on this in upcoming posts…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wife loves illustrating, photography and is now expanding into videography to share our story and experiences via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC2dzWCzIcp7PkRuGxSH4ATQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Youtube&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/lauza_and_michael&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; to hopefully inspire others to do what they love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we are sharing our journey, our learnings and everything that comes with this new way of living via Youtube, Instagram and a soon to come website, I want to keep writing my personal, more work related, experiences here on my personal blog as I find this helping me to bring more consciousness to my actions and decisions.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">“Hello World” is often the first program written by people learning to code, and is often used to illustrate the basic syntax of a programming language.</summary></entry></feed>